<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Entirely Different Matters</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Entirely Different Matters</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 19:34:45 +0530</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Projects</title>
      <link>/projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 19:34:45 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/projects/</guid>
      <description>Some stuff I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on:
 Anki Card Maker: I wanted to improve my Kannada vocabulary, so I built a scraping tool that creates flashcards for Anki. Youtube to Transcript: Youtube has some great longform content but I just do not have the time to watch 30min+ long videos. However, I can just skim through it much faster if I had it in text. This script fetches the user-created/auto-generated subtitles and adds punctuation using a great ML-based Python package I found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using OpenCV with C&#43;&#43;</title>
      <link>/posts/opencv_cpp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 Jul 2022 19:08:51 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/opencv_cpp/</guid>
      <description>I ran into lots of issues trying to get the SFM example to work with C++, mostly linking errors. Installing Ceres and its dependencies was a breeze. The problem, however, was that the SFM libraries were not detecting Ceres, and so weren&amp;rsquo;t being included. To fix it, I had to add:
#define CERES_FOUND 1 before I included the SFM libraries. This fixed the SFM issues but I still faced issues with the VIZ module, until I realized I just had not added that dependency to cmake.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Can&#39;t into Forestry</title>
      <link>/posts/cant_into_forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 18 Jul 2022 20:13:36 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/cant_into_forestry/</guid>
      <description>I found forestry so confusing to use. It&amp;rsquo;s one of those blocky websites that trades usability for &amp;ldquo;accessible&amp;rdquo; user experience. A trend I&amp;rsquo;ve seen in a lot of modern websites. Hard pass. I&amp;rsquo;ll stick to text editors and bash scripts for now.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About</title>
      <link>/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 01:18:54 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m Vathsa, a Robotics Engineer by profession and an amateur at everything else. I&amp;rsquo;m interested in STEM, Internet culture, Music, and Literature, and I wish I had the time for a lot more. I created this mainly with the intention of documenting my projects.
I&amp;rsquo;ll post all sorts of stuff here, and this is not a resume/portfolio. Views expressed here are my own and do not represent my employers&amp;rsquo; in any way.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Ricing = Procrastination</title>
      <link>/posts/first_post/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 06 Jun 2022 00:37:07 +0530</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/first_post/</guid>
      <description>I finally got a work laptop. Finally. It was worth the wait though, I now have a shiny new top of the line gaming laptop with a glowing RGB star on the lid. But oh, they forgot a webcam.
I was looking forward to this for weeks. Just me and my laptop. I was fantasizing about all the projects I could finally do, all the shitty memes I could make on Photoshop, all the brilliantly written, beautifully designed, post-modern indie video games that I had missed out on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I&#39;ve set up Forestry</title>
      <link>/posts/i-ve-set-up-forestry/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 05 Jun 2022 18:30:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/posts/i-ve-set-up-forestry/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m trying out Forestry, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to actually use Vim to write my posts like some basement dweller. So far, it seems straightforward but annoying to use if I want to do anything more than the bare minimum. In this case that&amp;rsquo;s a good thing. Anything that makes me write more and fuck around less.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>